乔 你马上要看到人生第一场雪啦
Joe, you're going to see your first snow.
-太令人激动了 -我等不及要做个雪银了
- It's so exciting! - I can't wait to make a snow person!
银
"Person"?
我们不能再让他上那个嬉皮学校了
We got to get him out of that hippie school.
别这样 杰
I don't know, Jay.
上次的成绩单上他得的是全海豚[全优]
Last report card, he got straight dolphins.
哥伦比亚的圣诞总是又热又嘈杂
Christmas in Colombia was always hot and loud,
人们争吵 背叛 阴谋
people arguing, betrayal, schemes.
所以我为全家租了座山顶小屋
So I rented a mountain cabin for the whole family
来庆祝我成为美国人后的第一个圣诞节
to celebrate my first Christmas as an American.
我想要一个白色圣诞节
I want a white christmas,
就像白人过的那种
You know, like white people have.
想在我们出发之前
Hey, want to hit the pipe one more time
再来一发吗
before we get on the road?
可以啊 试试也不错
Um, yeah. Couldn't hurt.
*平安夜*
*Silent night*
*圣善夜*
*Holy night*
天哪 我们太赞了
Oh, my God, we are killing it!
去年圣诞 米奇尔和我觉得
Last christmas, Mitchell and I thought it would be fun
给全家唱圣诞颂歌应该蛮好玩的
to sing a little Christmas carol for the family.
但可惜的是结果不是很好
Unfortunately, it didn't go so well
因为有些人喝得有点多
because somebody had a little too much to drink.
别晃你那小眼珠子了 我是当时太紧张了
Stop doing that. I was nervous.
*正是愉快的季节*
*'tis the season to be jolly*
*穿上欢庆[基佬]的服装*
*Don we now our gay apparel*
米奇尔
Mitchell?
全家人无情地嘲笑了我们一整年
The family has been mocking us relentlessly all year.
起了一堆绰号 像什么"尖声与赫伯"
Nicknames like Screeches & Herb,
"西蒙和真磕碜" "五分钱"
Simon & God-awful, Nickelback.
但是今年我们要挽回尊严
But we're gonna redeem ourselves this year.
我们已经为新曲子排练了好几个月
We have been rehearsing our new number for months,
我们会在小屋里首演
and we will debut it at the cabin
作为特别的节日打脸大礼送给全家
as a special holiday "Screw you" to the family.
马蒂 听我说
Hey, Marty, listen,
虽说你的宾馆你做主 但是你的客人们
it's your hotel, but a walnut closet
会想把他们的衣服挂在胡桃木衣柜里
is a place your guests want to hang their clothes.
要是木屑板衣柜 不如自挂东南枝
A particleboard closet -- they want to hang themselves.
天天谈衣柜都快把我搞疯了
All this closet stuff is driving me nuts.
我也想生气
I want to get annoyed,
但是我现在感觉太爽了 很难生气
but it's hard when I feel this comfortable.
老天 他又要开始说他的新大衣了
Oh, God, he's gonna talk about his new coat again.
就好像是有一只母羊抱着我一样温暖
It's like getting a big, warm hug from a mama sheep.
没什么比得上纯羊皮的感觉
Nothing feels like pure sheepskin.
买衣服的那姑娘说
The gal at the store said
我看着像克里斯·克里斯托佛森[美国音乐家]
I looked like Kris Kristofferson.
我们又不知道他是谁
We don't know who that is.
我这个假期
I have so much lab homework
有超多实验作业要做
to get done during this break.
要是我能做决定
If it were up to me,
我不会让今年的圣诞到来
Christmas wouldn't even come this year.
你还能更像卡通里的坏人一点吗
Any chance you could sound more like a cartoon villain?
拜托 艾丽克斯 整整三天的冬日欢乐
Come on, Alex, it's three solid days of winter fun.
我们要坐雪橇 滑冰
We're gonna go sledding, skating,
冰钓 做雪天使
ice-fishing, make snow angels.
谁跟我一起 雪 雪
Who's with me?! Snow, snow!
雪 雪 雪 雪 雪 雪
Snow, snow, snow, snow, snow, snow, snow!
那是雪吗
Snow?
不是 那是叶子
No, that's a leaf.
这里比家里还热呢
It's hotter here than at home.
歌洛莉亚 你的每日邮件里
Gloria, in your little daily e-mails,
说的可是会很冷啊
you said it was gonna be cold.
我的手机上就是这么写的啊
That's what my phone said.
你用的是摄氏度
You're on celsius.
会很热哦 各位
It's going to be hot, guys!
火炉开着呢吗
Oh, is the furnace on?!
菲尔 快把外套脱了吧
Phil, take off that jacket.
看着你我都觉得浑身发热
You're making me hot just looking at you.
售货员说过会有这个效果
Saleslady said that would happen.
相信我 我凉爽如黄瓜
Trust me, I'm cool as cucumber.
这衣服好像懂得我的身体需要什么一样
Something about the coat just knows what my body needs.
你现在像海洛因上瘾了一样流着汗呢
You're sweating like a heroin addict.
快看 有钢琴呢
Oh, hey, look, a piano.
要不听"唱崩的哥俩"[卡朋特兄妹]唱首歌吧
Maybe we can get a little song from the Crapenters.
冷静
Be cool.
安迪的未婚妻贝丝得工作
Andy's fiancee, Beth, has to work,
所以歌洛莉亚请他来过圣诞
so Gloria invited him for Christmas,
情况很复杂
which is complicated
因为我们俩滚床单了 但是没人知道
because we've been having sex and nobody knows about it.
当然 我们自己知道
I mean, we know.
不能让我家人知道我们的事情
My family cannot find out about us.
我当然不会告诉他们
I'm certainly not gonna tell them.
他们还算尊重我
I still have their respect.
安迪 快点 乔做出想大号的表情了
Andy, chop-chop. Joe's making his bathroom face.
好了 我们快回家吧
All right, let's just go home.
这里这么热 又没有无线
I mean, it's hot. There's no wi-fi.
艾丽克斯 别这么扫兴
Alex, stop being the grinch.
如果这是最糟糕的问题 那祝你圣诞快乐
If that is the worst problem, then merry Christmas.
谢天谢地 你们都来了
Oh, thank God you made it!
我还以为你们出车祸了呢
I thought you'd gotten into a horrible car accident!
等等
Wait a second.
你们不是特里普 塔德 洛伊斯 达西和马琳
You're not Trip, Tad, Lois, Darcy, and Marlene.
-不是 我们有别的名字 -你们是谁
- No, we're other names. - Who are you?
费格·威尔逊
Fig Wilson.
我们全家每年都在这里过圣诞
My family's been coming here for the holidays for years.
我们就是从威尔逊家把这个小屋租过来的
We rented this cabin from the Wilsons.
-他们去夏威夷了 -没人跟我说过啊
- They are in Hawaii. - Nobody told me that.
那就只能 再见啦
Okay, well, bye-bye.
他们怎么能抛下我啊
How could they abandon me?
我是家里最体贴的人啊
Uh, I'm the most caring one in the family.
我警告他们小心癌症
I warn them about cancer.
我给他们的胖小孩买"超乎想象"尺寸的衣服
I buy their fat kids clothes in aspirational sizes.
我请他们所有人来参加我狗狗的葬礼
I invite them all to my dogs' funerals.
上一只狗直接冲到车流里
Last one ran straight into traffic.
我能理解原因
I can see that.
有没有可能是邀请函搞丢了
Is it possible the invitation got lost?
你看上去很不错啊
I mean... you seem great.
那我就去拿我的包走下山吧
Well, I guess I'll just get my bags and walk down the hill.
希望我能在天黑前赶到巴士站
Hopefully, I'll get to the bus station before nightfall.
现在是狼出没的季节
It's wolf season.
你何不跟我们一起过呢
Why don't you stay here with us?
圣诞节啊
It's Christmas.
我第一眼看到你的时候
First time I saw you,
还以为你会是那种刺儿头
I thought you were gonna be a pain in the ass,
但结果你是我的最爱啊
but it turns out you're my favorite.
你们觉得里面是什么东西啊
What do you think's in here?
没人告诉你那个被遗忘男孩的传说吗
No one told you the legend of the Forgotten Boy?
一百年前就是在这里发生的
Happened right here 100 years ago.
一个男孩非常坏
A boy was very bad,
所以他父母把他锁在这个秘密的房间里
and his parents locked him in this secret room
任由他在这里自生自灭
and left him here forever.
他们说在夜里 你能听到他
They say at night, you can hear him
努力挠墙要爬出来的声音
trying to scratch his way out.
我们吓到她了
We got her.
蠢货
Idiots.
刚才是你在挠墙 对吧
That was you scratching, right?
抱歉
Oh, sorry.
-你先走 -没关系 你先
- No, you go. - No, it's okay. After you.
我就...
Here, I'll just...
我干嘛不
Oh, why don't I go...
你们俩在干嘛 瞪眼比赛吗
What are you guys doing -- having a staring contest?
我赢过很多次哦
I got winners!
晚点再说 先跟我来
Later, though. Come here.
安迪
Andy...
我要送你一个特别的礼物
I've got a very special present for you.
这家伙告诉你他考到地产经纪执照了吗
Did this guy tell you he passed his real-estate-license test?
我知道 我帮他背书[塞进去]的
I know. I helped him cram.
她逼[扭]我逼得可紧了
Ah, she's really drilling me pretty hard.
真棒 听我说 我刚进入房地产行业时
Cool. Listen, when I first got into real estate,
进了一间要穿西装上班的大公司
I worked at one of those big firms with the blazers.
我还是别提公司的名字了
I'd rather not say their name,
不过名字压的是"世纪地产好无聊"的韵
but it rhymed with "Century not very fun."
不管怎样 我保留了这件
Anyway, I saved this.
我想把它送给你
I'd like for you to have it.
穿上之后 你要牢记我们这一行的价值观
When you wear it, remember the values of our profession --
信任 尊重 诚信 忠实和纯粹
Trust, honor, integrity, fidelity, and purity.
你能配得上这件西装外套吗 安迪
Are you worthy of the blazer, Andy?
我会的
I want to be.
我没想到会这么激动
I didn't expect it to hit this hard.
我也是
Me either.
谁想来点蛋奶酒
Who wants eggnog?
我要来点 这周工作太辛苦了
I'll take some. I had a tough week at work.
你是做什么的
What do you do?
我父亲和我身处橱柜行业
Oh, my dad and I are in the closet business.
什么 我差点听成"橱柜行业"
I'm sorry, it almost sounded like you said, "Closet business".
我专门负责解决住宅及酒店储物问题
I did -- residential and hospitality storage solutions.
无聊
Yikes.
小不点儿 我快无聊死了
Hey, specks, I'm dying over there.
你在看什么呢
What are you reading?
关于科学的 你肯定会觉得很无聊
Science stuff. I'm sure it'll bore you.
我在麻省理工教天体物理学
I teach astrophysics at M.I.T.
等等
Wait a minute.
-你是F.N.威尔逊吗 -正是在下
- Are you F.N. Wilson? - F-N right, I am!
我们刚读完你写的那篇太阳耀斑
We just read your essay on how solar flares
会怎样毁掉地球生命的文章
will wipe out life on earth!
希望是在橱柜女士对上我之前
Hopefully before closet lady corners me again.
大家都在这里
Everybody's here,
所以我们就放松点
So let's just casually
慢慢靠近钢琴
make our way over to the piano.
你喝的是什么啊 斯嘉丽[猩红]小姐
Ooh, what are we drinking there, Miss Scarlet?
放轻松 是热茶 对我嗓子好
Relax. It's hot tea for my throat.
我们最好让莉莉来摄影
Oh, we should have Lily film us.
莉莉 过来
Hey, Lily, come here.
大爸和我等一下
Okay, so, Daddy and I are about
要唱一首圣诞歌 然后...
to sing a Christmas song, and --
我现在就要打断你们
I'm gonna stop you right there.
不 这次跟去年不一样
No, it's not gonna be like last year
因为我们精心准备了 而且唱的是《平安夜》
because we're prepared and we're singing "Silent Night".
我最喜欢那首歌了 我能跟你们一起唱吗
That's my favorite. Can I sing with you?
大家请听我说两句
Can I have everyone's attention, please?
我能够跟任何人梦寐以求
I feel so lucky celebrating
最棒的家人一起庆祝节日简直无比幸运
with the best damn family any man could hope for.
老爸
Dad.
-当然还有费格 -大家好
- And Fig. - Hey, all!
歌洛莉亚和我经过一段时间的讨论
Gloria and I have been talking about this for a while.
乔也越来越大了
What with Joe getting older,
我觉得是时候开始人生新篇章了
I feel it's just the right time to start a new chapter,
因此我决定 退休
which is why I've decided... to retire.
-天哪 -什么
- Oh, my. - What?!
也许"退休"这个词用得不对
Maybe "Retired" is the wrong word --
这更像是一种角色转换
more of a transition.
所以要是有人问杰·普里契特去哪了
So, when people ask, "Where's Jay Pritchett?"
你们可以告诉他们 他转换[变性]去了
you tell them, "He's transitioning".
好吧 我也发现了
Oay, I heard it, too.
还是用"退休"吧
Let's go back to retiring.
我们俩终于可以租那辆房车
Hey, we can finally rent that R.V.
去各大棒球队主场转转了
and visit all of the Major League ballparks.
你还是自己去吧
You can probably go ahead and do that alone.
总之 我当然得好好考虑
Uh, anyway, I had to ask myself,
由谁接手公司最合适
"Who's the best person to lead the company?"
答案很明显
And the answer is obvious.
-查克·菲尼 -谁
- Chuck Feeny. - Who?
芝加哥来的无名少年
Gutters and screen hot shot out of Chicago.
有他担起公司重任
With him in charge,
我们也都可以高枕无忧了
we can all relax knowing that the company is in good hands.
克莱尔也会有个很棒的新老板
Claire gets a great new boss.
你们也能有更多的时间跟我相处
And you all get to spend more time with yours truly.
敬克莱尔的新老板
Well, to this one's new boss.
克莱尔 这是我做手势的手
Claire, that's my gesturing hand.
工作时需要它
I need it for work.
我一周工作60个小时 就为了让
I work 60-hour weeks so Chuck Feeny can have
查克·菲尼能享有橱柜大会上最棒的位置
the corner office and the best table at closet con!
亲爱的 你走慢点
Honey, you need to slow down.
这件衣服我还没穿惯 走不快
This coat isn't quite broken in yet.
听着 你完全有权生气
Listen, you have every right to be mad.
所有人都知道那个位置是你应得的
Everyone knows you deserve that job.
想想看我那么多个周末的加班
And to think of all the weekends I worked
那些被迫取消的家庭休假
and the -- the family vacations we've put off,
更别提我受到的压力还有失眠
not to mention the stress and the insomnia and --
过来
Come here.
克莱尔 人生就像蜿蜒的山路
Claire, life's like a mountain road...
每个转角都有新的奇遇在等着你
with a new adventure around every corner.
如果这是这件大衣的广告词
If that's the slogan for this stupid coat,
-我就杀了你 -别说话 抱紧我
- I'm gonna kill you! - Shh! Get in here.
-你见到克莱尔了吗 -没有
- Have you seen Claire? - No.
我告诉过你查克·菲尼这主意很糟
I told you this Chuck Feeny thing was a terrible idea!
这主意超棒的
It's a brilliant idea.
根本没有什么查克·菲尼
There is no Chuck Feeny.
我编了这么个人 是因为我看到唐·麦克索里
I made him up because of what happened to Don McSorley
把公司传给他儿子的结果
when he turned his company over to his son.
他儿子接受公司只是因为觉得自己有责任
Son only took the job because he felt obligated.
一年以后 公司破产了
One year later, business went bankrupt.
我"悲痛"地花了原价8%的钱买下了
Broke my heart to buy his entire inventory
他所有的库存
8 cents on the dollar.
我这么做是为了克莱尔
I'm doing this for Claire.
她会竭尽全力让我开心
She'd do anything to make me happy,
而我不希望那是她接手公司的原因
and that's not why I want her to take the job.
如果她想要 她就得努力去争取
If she wants it, she'll fight for it.
如果不是 那我就给了她轻松离场的借口
If not, I just gave her an easy out.
我能想到十种比这个好的方法
I can think of 10 better ways to do this.
放松 结果一定会很棒的
Relax. It's gonna be perfect.
她会来找我要属于她的东西
She'll come to me, demand what's hers.
我会告诉她真相 拥抱她 完美的圣诞节
I'll tell her the truth, big hug, perfect Christmas.
-我真是太聪明了 -你真是疯了
- I'm a genius. - You're a crazy person.
在我们村子 我们会往你脖子上帮个易拉罐
In my village, we will tie a tin can around your neck
这样听声音就知道你来了
to know when you're coming.
*平安夜*
*Silent night*
*圣善夜*
*Holy night*
*真宁静*
*All is calm*
*真光明*
*All is bright*
*圣光环绕圣母圣婴*
*'round yon virgin mother and child*
我有个好主意
Okay, hey, hey, I have a fun idea!
我们不如现在就把礼物拿一个给莉莉
Why don't we give Lily one of her presents right now?
这主意不错 二爸
That is a fun idea, Daddy.
这样她就能去玩玩具
Then she can go play with a toy
而不是跟我们两个无聊的老男人待在一起
rather than being with us boring, old adults.
听起来怎么样 莉莉
How's that sound, Lily?
我觉得你们有什么阴谋 不过不关我事
I feel like you're up to something, but I don't care.
我要礼物 我要那个自行车形状的
I want a present. I'll take the bike-shaped one.
顺便说一句 包得挺不错的
Nice wrapping job, by the way.
那不是给乔的吗
Uh, wasn't that for Joe?
这下乔要收到洋娃娃了
Well, Joe's getting a doll now.
歌洛莉亚让我取木柴
Gloria asked me to get some kindling.
你为什么仿佛什么都没穿地到处晃
Why are you walking around wearing next to nothing?
外面可有26度
It's 26 celsius out there.
你看 我可是穿得严严实实的
Ah, I'm not showing any skin
免得诱惑到你
'cause I don't want to tempt you.
你这金闪闪的外套保准让人性致全无
Oh, well, your gold blazer took care of that.
-你明明已经欲火难耐了 -是啊 为什么
- You know you're into it. - I know. Why?
你真讨厌 还有你那犀利帅气的眼神
Damn you and that eagle scout smile.
我也为你那迷人的大眼睛而沉醉
I want to take a swim in those big doe eyes.
开闸泄洪
This is happening.
-拿到柴火[硬]了吗 安迪 -什么
- Getting wood, Andy? - What?!
你能相信歌洛莉亚想弄传统的篝火吗
Can you believe Gloria wants a traditional fire?
就好像这儿还不够热似的
As if it isn't hot enough in here.
来吧 伙计
Come on, bro.
你好 莉莉
Hello, Lily.
你们穿的这是什么
What are you wearing?
老妈让我们穿上圣诞毛衣
Mom made us put on our Christmas sweaters,
但是你看看我们发现了什么
but look what we found.
这上面有留言
It's a note.
"我渴望饮用小女孩的鲜血"
"I'm hungry for the blood of a little girl."
"落款是被遗忘的男孩"
"Signed, the forgotten boy."
太恐怖了
This is terrifying.
这下来真的了
It's getting real.
最可怕的是他的拼写和两岁小孩的一样差
The scariest thing is that he spells like a 2-year-old.
等等 你说什么
Wait, what?
给点力好吧
Dude.
这就是圣诞节
Christmas, huh?
谁出的这么糟糕的主意
Who the hell came up with this one?
康斯坦丁大帝
It was Emperor Constantine.
真厉害
I love it!
身为这屋里最聪明的人可不是容易的事
It's not easy being the smartest person in the room.
我姐姐以为量子论是个游戏节目的名字
My sister thinks quantum theory is a game show,
我弟弟还试过把裤子从头上脱下来
and my brother once tried to take his pants off over his head.
像咱们这样的姑娘早看清了家里的蠢事
Gals like us, we see through all the family B.S..
事事都门儿清
We call it like we see it.
所以 如果我们在圣诞节
So, if we're alone for Christmas
或是生日和周末落单了 那是他们的损失
and birthdays and weekends, it's their loss.
像咱们这样的姑娘从不需要有人作伴
Gals like us we don't need anyone.
我不喜欢神叨叨 但是很明显
I'm not big on mysticism, but, clearly,
这个女人是我未来独自庆祝圣诞的幻影
this woman was my ghost of Christmas future.
所以我决定力挽狂澜
So, I decided to turn things around
投入到节日的气氛之中
and jump in on the holiday spirit.
跳上"玩乐"号列车喽
Jump aboard the fun train!
那是火车启动的音效
That was a train.
这气味可真是香啊
Something smells good!
什么 什么糊了
What? What doesn't smell good?
不 我说香
No, I-I said it did.
我糊涂了 哪一点不合你心意了
I am confused! What is it that you don't like?!
只是期待一下晚餐而已 我是爱你们的
I'm just excited for dinner. I love you guys.
别这么刻薄 我们尽全力了
Oh, don't be nasty. We're trying our best.
就是
Yes!
看看我找到了什么 神秘之屋的钥匙
Hey, look what I found -- a key to that secret room.
我的全家都在这里
My entire family is here.
你知道那么做有多危险吗
Do you have any idea how dangerous that is?
两分钟后见
Meet me in two minutes.
你终于出现了
There she is.
我宣布完大事以后就没再看见你
Haven't seen you since my big announcement.
你觉得怎么样
What do you think?
我觉得我把我的一切都贡献给了公司
I think that I gave my all to this company
然后如果你要让别的人接管掌权
and that if you were gonna hand over the reins to somebody,
那应该是我 而不是什么芝加哥无名小卒
it should be me and not some hump from Chicago!
我碰巧想告诉你
Well, it just so happens --
我还没说完 老爸
I'm not finished, Dad!
谢谢你救了我
Thank you for saving me
让我接下来的20年免受
from wasting the next 20 years of my life
整日谈论板条 长杆还有铰链的烦闷
talking about slats, rods, and hinges --
让我不用再在世上最无聊的行当里
from becoming the most boring person
做那个最无聊的人
in the most boring industry on earth!
-"无聊"吗 -无聊
- "Boring"?! - Boring!
是衣柜让混乱的世界变得井然有序
Closets bring order to a chaotic world!
-怎么了 -我告诉你怎么回事吧
- What happened? - I'll tell you what happened.
我养了一个自私的没良心的女儿
I raised a mean, ungrateful daughter,
然后我很庆幸让查克·菲尼来接管公司
and I'm glad I gave the business to Chuck Feeny!
根本就没有查克·菲尼这个人
There is no Chuck Feeny!
曼尼 卢克 你们够了
Manny, Luke, knock it off!
这么逗我一点意思都没有
No one thinks it's funny!
你是在跟我们说话吗
Are you talking to us?
既然大家都坐好了 那么
Hey, as long as everybody's just sitting around, uh --
他们要再唱一首
Oh, they're gonna do another one!
谢谢 圣诞老人
Thank you, Santa Claus!
挺逗的
That's hilarious.
你们继续笑 等下你们就笑不起来了
Hope you're having fun, 'cause that's about to end.
行了 跟着计划走 亲爱的
Okay, stick to the scripted patter, sweetie.
预备 一 二
And a one and a two.
*平安夜*
*Silent night*
我天 那是怎么回事
Oh, my god, what was that?
-肯定没事 -没事的
- Oh, I'm sure it's fine. - Fine. It's no big deal.
那么米奇尔 我们从头唱起
So, Mitchell, here we go again.
*平安夜*
*Silent night*
是你们女儿在叫
That is your daughter screaming!
-莉莉 你没事吧 -怎么回事
- Lily, are you okay?! - What's going on?!
被遗忘的男孩 我听见了 他在里面
The Forgotten Boy -- I heard him! He's in there!
-他在里头哦 -我们让他出来好吗
- Of course he is. - All right, let's get him out, huh?
-我们会保证他不再来烦 -老天
- We'll make sure that he doesn't bother -- - Oh, god!
我的天
Oh, god!
安迪
Andy?
把那件外套脱下来
Take off the blazer.
我们只是在找晚饭用的餐巾纸
We were just looking for dinner napkins.
在哪儿找 她的衣服里面吗
Where? In her shirt?
我有好多问题想问
I have so many questions.
男生们 莉莉 去本该有雪的地方玩吧
Boys, Lily, go play where snow would be.
这是怎么一回事儿
So, is this a thing?
你们这是头一回吗
Is it the first time?
-不是 -是的
- No. - Yes!
安迪
Andy!
我不想再说谎了
I-I'm sick of the lies.
我们一直有着不正当的关系
We've been having improper relations.
你不是已经订婚了吗
Aren't you engaged?
这会儿你倒想起忠诚来了
Oh, suddenly, you're concerned about loyalty.
原来你在跟我说话 不会觉得无聊吗
Oh, you're talking to me. Won't that bore you?
-很明显我就是这么无聊 -听着 各位
- Apparently, I'm boring! - Listen, everyone,
别让这事搅黄了我们美好的节日
let's not let this ruin our beautiful holiday.
艾丽克斯 现在没人要听你的讽刺
Alex, nobody needs your sarcasm right now!
不要幸灾乐祸 亲爱的
It's ugly, honey.
这是安迪和海莉的私事而已
This is Andy and Haley's private business.
我觉得我们应该关注的是这特别的夜晚
I think we should be focused on this special night.
这特别平安的平安夜
This special silent night.
一 二 走起
One and a two.
*平安夜*
*Silent night*
-*圣善--* -各位 我有个惊喜给你们
- *Hol--* - Guys, I have a surprise!
那就是贝丝
It's Beth!
我的老天
Oh, my god.
这是我准备的圣诞惊喜其中之一
This is one of my Christmas surprises.
安迪 你还是可以和未婚妻一起过圣诞
Andy, you can spend Christmas with your fiancé after all!
-小宝贝 -小南瓜
- Hi, bittle-battle! - Hey, pumpkin!
贝丝 不介意我和你男人先聊两句吧
Beth, you mind if I have a quick chitchat with your man?
就是 我带贝丝参观参观这房子
Yeah, I'll give Beth a tour of the house
你们让歌洛莉亚了解最新情况
while we get Gloria up to speed.
你肯定也超爱节日吧
Don't you just love the holidays?
奇妙满满 惊喜满满 还有
Full of wonder and magic and surprise and --
什么鬼
What?!
坐下
Sit.
邓菲先生 我非常...
Mr. Dunphy, I am s--
没轮到你说话
It's not your turn to talk.
那是我的女儿 而你已经跟别人订婚了
That's my daughter, and you're engaged to someone else.
如果只是一时兴起 那就结束它 明白吗
If this is a fling, it's over. You understand me?
但如果你们来真的
But if this is something real,
你必须跟贝丝坦白
you need to be honest with Beth.
是时候像个男人一样负起责任来了
It's time to step up and be a man.
我明白了
I understand.
让我告诉你些事
Let me tell you something.
人生就像蜿蜒的山路
Life is like a mountain road
每个转角都有新的奇遇在等着你
with a new adventure around every corner.
很赞吧
Right?
-你刚自己想出来的吗 -是的
- Did you just think of that? - I did.
气氛似乎有点紧张
Seems tense.
你姐姐是个大麻烦 对吧
Your big sis is kind of a disaster, huh?
费格 如你所说 我们有很多相像的地方
Fig, we are a lot alike, like you said.
有些时候我们可以下意识
And sometimes we can give off
就将负面的情绪释放出去
a negative vibe without meaning to.
你想说什么
What's your point?
我在想 也许我们可以再努力一点
Well, I was thinking maybe we could make more of an effort
更积极一些 真正去享受圣诞节
to be more positive and actually enjoy Christmas.
像个傻子一样吗
As a goof?
好吧 这样 新计划
Okay, all right, new plan.
我们等海莉和安迪的事结束以后
We wait until the whole Haley/Andy thing blows over.
-每个人都微醺了 -除你以外
- Everyone gets a little liquored up. - Other people.
然后 就在饭后甜点前 你坐到钢琴前
And then, right before dessert, you sit down at the piano.
-*平安夜* -外面搞什么
- *Silent night* - What the hell is that?
*圣善夜*
*Holy night*
*真宁静*
*All is calm*
*真光明*
*All is bright*
*圣光环绕圣母圣婴*
*Round yon virgin mother and child*
-真见鬼 -我他...
- Son of a bitch! - Mother...
*圣洁婴孩纯真可爱*
*Holy infant, so tender and mild*
*尽享天赐安眠*
*Sleep in heavenly peace*
不管了 我要喝酒
That's it. I'm drinking.
*尽享天赐安眠*
*Sleep in heavenly peace*
悲催套餐 再续一年
That's got to hurt!
西葫芦花
Hey, zucchini blossom!
虾米花 听我说
Hey, popcorn shrimp, listen.
出了点事 而且...
Something is going on, and...
虽然很令人伤感 但我想我们还是该谈一下
As painful as it may be, I think we should talk about it.
你总是能看透我的内心
You could always see through me.
-怎么回事 -是的 我认识了一个人
- What now? - Yes, I met someone.
我背着你跟他好了有几个月了
I've been dating him for a few months behind your back.
我给他也戴绿帽子了
And I'm actually cheating on him, too.
是指我给他戴的吗
You mean with me?
不
No!
No.
虾米花
Popcorn shrimp.
计划微调
Well, slight change of plans.
我要走了
I'm gonna be going.
祝大家圣诞快乐
Merry Christmas, everyone.
再见 贝丝
Bye, Beth!
开车注意安全
Drive safe!
保持联络
Keep in touch!
我觉得跟她不会再跟我们联络了
I don't see us keeping in touch.
你跟贝丝分手了吗
Hey, you broke up with Beth?
她劈腿了 真难以置信
She cheated on me. I can't believe it.
-等等 你很难过吗 -当然会难过
- Wait, you're upset? - Of course I'm upset.
我们在一起十年了
We dated for 10 years.
我觉得被人从背后捅了一刀
I just got stabbed in the back.
-欢迎加入我们的阵营 -不是吧
- Welcome to the club. - Really?
你被从背后捅过一刀吗
You were stabbed in the back?
女儿嘲弄自己父亲的人生
A daughter mocking her father's life.
衣橱并没那么好 从何时开始的
Closets aren't fascinating? Since when?
想聊聊背叛的话题吗
Want to talk about betrayal?
你们觉得有人偷了别人的歌
How about when somebody steals a song
然后占为己有这事怎么样
and takes it for themselveses?
我不知道你们打算唱那首歌
I had no idea that you guys were gonna sing that song.
我知道 我听见他们彩排了
I did. I heard them rehearsing.
我还以为墙里困了只动物呢
I thought there was an animal stuck in the wall.
别忘了是我们邀请你来我门家的
And to think we invited you into our home.
我们真该把你留在外面热着
We should've left you out in the warm.
我明白你很生气 不过别忘了
I get that you're upset, but remember,
你胖的时候我依然喜欢你
I even liked you when you were fat.
他们给我们这样的人颁奖
They give out awards to people like me!
我放弃了去卡波的三天旅行
I gave up a three-day trip to Cabo
就为了敲定那个最好的西部合约
to close that best Western deal.
没错 你欠她25杯玛格丽特酒
That's right. You owe her 25 margaritas!
-菲尔 -21杯
- Phil! - 21!
-21杯 -够了 够了
- 21! - Enough, enough, enough!
我只想过个白人过的圣诞节
All I wanted was a white Christmas,
所以我没回哥伦比亚
and instead, I'm back in Colombia --
这燥热 这些背叛 还有人偷歌
the heat, the betrayal, people stealing songs!
现在到此为止
This ends now!
安迪 别抱怨了 你该感激海莉会喜欢你
Andy, stop whining and be grateful that Haley likes you!
她是实打实的满分女神 你去犹他也算不上帅
She's a stone-cold 10, and you're a Utah 7!
杰 你该亲克莱尔跟她言归于好
Jay, it's time for you and Caire to kiss and make up!
他为什么不去亲查克·菲尼
Why doesn't he kiss Chuck Feeny?!
因为根本没有查克·菲尼这个人
Because there's no Chuck Feeny!
他编出来考验你的
He made it up to test you!
如果她根本不在乎的话 就不会这么难过了
And if she didn't care, she wouldn't be this upset!
根本没有查克·菲尼吗
There is no Chuck Feeny?
这是个愚蠢的主意
It was a dumb idea,
不过我目睹了唐·麦克索里的结局
but I saw what happened to Don McSorley!
那个杰出的百叶窗商人
The crackerjack blinds guy.
你只花了原价8%的钱就买下了他的整个公司
You got his whole company for 8 cents on the dollar.
我才花了7块就把他的复印机买了
I bought his photocopier for 7 bucks.
我一直都希望你能接手公司
I always hoped you'd take over the company.
没人比你更受我信任了
There's no one I trust more than you.
我只是想知道这是否真是你想要的
I just had to know that you really wanted it!
你想知道我是否愿意经营一间不仅能为人提供
That I wanted to run a company that gives people a place
存放衣物的场所 还可以存放梦想的公司吗
to store not only their jeans, but their dreams?
-我愿意 -给
- Yes! - Here.
提前把圣诞礼物送给你
I got you a little early Christmas present.
克莱尔·邓菲 总裁
"Claire Dunphy, C.E.O."
你啊
Oh, you!
这还差不多
That's more like it!
谁还在乎外面天气如何
Who cares what the weather is?
重要的是我们拥有彼此
What is important is that we have each other!
雪
Snow!
仁君温瑟拉[圣诞颂歌] 下雪了
Good King Wenceslas, there is snow!
我说了一切都会好起来的
I told you everything was going to work out.
真是个完美的圣诞节
It's a perfect Christmas.
-你们看什么呢 -雪
- What are we looking at? - Snow!
圣诞节的奇迹
Our miracle for Christmas.
那不是雪
That's not snow.
那是森林大火的灰尘
That's ashes from a forest fire.
如果你们安静下来 能听到有人尖叫的
If you're quiet, you can hear screaming.
菲尔 你查看过所有的抽屉了吗
Phil, did you look in all the drawers?
是的 床底下也看了 什么也没落下
Yep, and under the bed. Got everything.
-再见 歌洛莉亚 谢谢你 -再见
- Bye, Gloria. Thank you. - Bye.
杰 别忘了乔的新洋娃娃
Jay, don't forget Joe's new doll.
米奇和小卡总是想把人逼上断背山
Mitch and Cam -- always pushing their agenda.
再见 房子
Bye-bye, house!
我们会想念你的
We will miss you!
有人吗
Hello?
Hello?!
是我 卢克
I-it's me -- Luke!
我好像把自己锁在这里了
I think I locked myself in here!
这里好像还有别的什么东西
I don't think I'm alone here.